# **SUSANNA KLINE**

<u>susannakline@gmail.com</u> | 217-766-3203 | Champaign, IL (seeking remote or hybrid work) <u>linkedin.com/in/susanna-kline</u>

# **Summary of qualifications**

Highly skilled technical writer and editor with 10+ years of experience, a strong background as a frontend engineer, and 20+ total years in content development. My affinity for research and learning allows me to improve user experience by creating clear documentation for all levels of technical audiences.

# Languages and frameworks

HTML, CSS, Markdown, JavaScript, React, GraphQL, REST APIs, TypeScript, Cypress

### Tools and skills

Git, GitHub, Jira, backstage.io TechDocs, Confluence, G-Suite, Docs-as-Code, Agile

# Work experience

Ad Hoc LLC (remote)

2021-2023

Senior Technical Writer (2022-2023)

- In four months, organized and developed content for seven Veterans Affairs (VA) Platform Console Playbooks
  using Agile Docs-as-Code processes for stakeholders, software engineers, and Console administrators.
  Documentation contents included software operations and maintenance, catalog onboarding, design system,
  plugins, and health metrics.
- Supported engineers, researchers, and designers with content strategy and development, translating highly technical information into clear text, sample code, illustrations, and videos.
- Tested technical workflows and wrote documentation to support VA Forms Library, decreasing support requests over a three-month period.
- Collaborated with product managers, SMEs, and stakeholders to develop audience-appropriate, high-quality technical content for internal and external users.
- Researched and designed Product Management training course comprehensive outline containing product
  management and basic software engineering concepts. Tailored the course for stakeholders and product
  managers working in the government space and positioned it to compete with top certification courses.
- Supported growth team on \$100M+ contract proposals, providing technical writing on topics including DevOps, security, data science, cloud computing, CI/CD, microservices, and product management.

Software Engineer III (2021-2022)

Developed VA Forms Library components in open-source repos using React and TypeScript.

#### **Mastery Logistics Systems (remote)**

2019-2021

Software Engineer (2020-2021)

- Developed new frontend features and modified existing codebase for transportation logistics software using React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Formik, GraphQL, REST APIs, and Cypress.
- Reorganized structure of React components in a complex portion of the app to eliminate errors and improve the maintainability of code.
- Drove Agile story and requirement creation for frontend features, collaborating with engineers and product managers on an eight-person team.

Software Engineering Apprentice (2019)

 Developed front-end features in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and GraphQL and presented final work to directors.

## SUSANNA KLINE

## **Manning Publications** (remote)

2011-2019

Team Lead | Senior Technical Content Developer | Trainer (2016-2019)

- Selected, led, and trained a team of five technical editors to produce software development courses for emerging and rapidly evolving technologies.
- Responsible for schedules, content strategy, and content development for technical books and video courses, demonstrating the ability to quickly grasp technical topics including machine learning, AI, performance monitoring, GraphQL, microservices, Docker, Amazon Web Services (AWS), d3.js, and APIs.

### Senior Technical Content Developer | Trainer (2014-2016)

- Trained new technical editors on instructional design, content strategy, learning theory, and internal procedures
  while continuing to manage an average of 8-10 book projects. Book topics included JavaScript on Things
  (hardware), d3.js, Go, web performance, the MEAN stack, AWS, App Inventor: Android for Kids, ChucK,
  Ember.js, and hapi.js.
- Led documentation process improvement and new content initiatives to enhance team productivity.

## Technical Content Developer (2011-2014)

- Coached technical authors to improve technical content clarity, organization, and illustrations for higher quality and easier-to-understand book and video publications.
- Managed schedules and coordinated with authors and stakeholders to create timely, valuable software development books of 300-600 pages in 12-18 months. Book topics included machine learning, HBase, iOS development, SonarQube, Dart, Mondrian, and Windows IIS.

### **Independent Consultant**

2002-2018

Writer | Editor | UX Researcher

- Wrote UX research results and supported UX interviews for the University of Illinois CIO's office online learning engagement grant.
- Edited legal documentation for the Texas House of Representatives, translating difficult concepts into easy-to-understand, user-centered content for the public.
- Served as food and drink editor of a culture website. Wrote and edited articles featuring chefs, restaurants, and recipes. Managed freelance writers and photographers.
- Wrote engaging blog posts, newsletters, magazine articles, website content, encyclopedia entries, and training materials for clients. Subjects included business, engineering, medicine, accounting, and instructional design.
- Edited finance, technology, and fiction books for individuals and publishing companies.

#### Education

Udacity

Front-End Nanodegree

Two-time recipient of merit-based Grow with Google Scholarship, among top 10% awarded

Ouachita Baptist University, Magna Cum Laude

B.A. in Communications